fluke.com 2001-12-14

# Privacy Statement for www

Fluke Corporation has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to privacy, and to ensure you are aware of our latest position regarding privacy. Please note that this statement is subject to change, so we suggest you refer to it any time you may have questions regarding Fluke’s privacy practices relative to the web. The following discloses our current information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: [www.fluke.com](http://www.fluke.com/). 

The Fluke Corporation’s [www.fluke.com](http://www.fluke.com/) web site logs IP addresses and browser types, but we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. 

Therefore, you can browse this site without entering any personal information, and remain anonymous during your visit. 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information, and to help identify you. 

This site also includes a variety of registration and order forms that may ask for particular information about our visitors such as name, email address and demographic/product usage information. Information gathered through these means is used to learn more about our visitors, provide them with requested information, and to also mail them future informational/promotional materials from Fluke and its sales/service channel partners. You can request to not have informational/promotional materials sent to you, as noted in the "choice/opt out" section at the end of this notice. 

An exception is the employment application form that is located within our "employment" section of the site. Names received from these forms do not receive future informational/promotional materials from Fluke or our sales/service channel partners, and are kept on a confidential basis in our employment department for current and future employment opportunities.

Please also note that certain countries may not allow information (such as e-mail) to be transmitted outside of that country or region. If you have any concerns about this practice, we suggest you _do not_ use the forms or contact mechanisms included in this web site, and use an alternative form of contacting us. Refer to the "contact us" or "where to buy" portions of this web site for phone and mailing address information.

Details about the different means in which we gather information from visitors are detailed below:

****

**"Cookies"**

This site uses cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site. If a shopping cart feature is used, we would also use cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. If advertisements are used in the site, we would also use cookies to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. 

**

Registration Forms

**

This site's registration forms require users to give us contact information (like their name, email address, and some demographic data). We use this information to learn more about our visitors, and to keep visitors up to date on new products, services and developments. In some instances, Fluke or its distributors may use the customer's contact information to contact the visitor directly. 

**

Order Forms

**

This site uses order forms for customers to request information, materials, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address), and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and also to learn more about our customers. The customer's contact information may also be used by Fluke or its distributors to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. 

****

**Online Surveys**

Our online surveys may ask visitors for contact information (such as their email address), or other demographic or product usage data. We use data collected from these surveys to learn more about our customers, their likes and dislikes, and how we can improve our services and product offerings. Contact information collected is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Fluke or its distributors may also use the customer's contact information received in surveys to contact the visitor directly, if necessary. 

**

Contests

**

From time to time, this site features contests that ask visitors for contact information (like their email address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor to notify if they have won a prize in the contest. 

**

Employment Application Forms

**

This site includes employment application forms in the Employment section of the site. Information gathered through this form is kept confidential, not used for future informational or promotional mailings, and is used solely in the company’s employment offices for current and future employment opportunities. 

**

Public Forums

**

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**

Links

**

This site contains links to other sites. As such, www.fluke.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these Web sites.

**

Security

**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

**

"Choice/Opt-Out" of Receiving Future Informational/Promotional Materials

**

This site provides users the choice to "opt out" of receiving communications from Fluke and its sales/service channel partners.

If you **do not** wish to receive future informational or promotional messages and/or materials from Fluke or its sales/service channels, please send an e-mail to: fluke-info@fluke.com

**

Changes/Modifications

**

This site also gives users the option for changing and modifying information previously provided. Please send an e-mail to: fluke-info@fluke.com

**

Still Concerned?

**

If you are in any way concerned about providing information to Fluke via one of the above forms or methods, we suggest that you refrain from contacting Fluke via these methods, and contact us via phone or mail. Complete phone and mail information can be found in the "contact us" and "where to buy" sections of this web site.

**

Contacting the Web Site

**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact: 

Webmaster  
Fluke Corporation  
PO Box 9090, M/S 250E  
Everett, WA 98203  
fluke-info@fluke.com
